# SEOW HONG SIAH

#### **Audit Senior | Finance Professional**

Email: seowhs90@gmail.com, Mobile: 96922060, LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/hong-siah-seow-621bb058

## **SUMMARY**

Meticulous and diligent finance professional with audit experience in a wide spectrum of industries. Experienced in financial analysis and forecast modelling on listed companies. Possess a keen, analytical mind and in-depth understanding of the Singapore Financial Reporting Standards. Able to function well in a team setting or independently while meeting tight deadlines, and has demonstrated leadership capabilities in various facets of work and life.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Baker Tilly TFW LLP Sep 2015 to Present

Audit Senior

- Perform forecasting, discounted cash flow modelling and other valuation techniques on private and public MNCs.
- Adopt leadership role in audit engagements to plan, lead and execute audit procedures based on the Baker Tilly TFW LLP audit methodology.
- Perform financial analysis and industry analysis to evaluate clients' financial statement assertions.
- Lead and execute audit engagements on public and private entities in various industries including: Manufacturing, Commodities, Food and Beverages, Non-profit, Logistics, etc.
- Identify and discuss areas of improvement in clients' business models and internal controls based on financial analysis.
- Assess clients' financial health and performance using financial analysis and ratios.
- Determine and apply appropriate valuation techniques to clients' investments in accordance with FRS 113.
- Extract and analyze clients' financial data using Excel lookup and pivot table functions.
- Review and analyze clients' periodic financial reports and forecasts.

**C.S. Chan & Co.** May 2013 to Aug 2013

Audit Intern

- Assisted audit seniors with audit engagements with minimum guidance.
- Performed audit fieldwork and gained insight on implementing audit procedures to address risks.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Singapore Management University**

Aug 2011 to Jun 2015

Bachelor of Accountancy

• Extra-Curriculum Activities: Accounting Society Camp 2011, Sports Camp 2011.

Organizing committee for the two camps and involved in the management of logistics for camp participants.

## Lund University, School of Economics and Management

Jan 2014 to Jun 2014

International Student Exchange Program

#### Project Xin Yuan VI (Guangzhou)

Dec 2013 to Dec 2013

Overseas Community Service Project

- Participated as one of the Program Leaders in the organizing committee of a 2-weeks overseas community service program designed to teach and impart practical knowledge to the beneficiaries at the Guangzhou English Training Center for the Handicapped (GETCH).
- Lead a team of 12 members to teach practical musical skills, music theory and cultural exchange to classes of 25 students.

## **CERTIFICATION**

### **Institute of Singapore Chartered Accountant**

Jun 2016 to Sep 2018 (Expected)

Chartered Accountant (CA)

## **SKILLS**

• Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, financial analysis, valuation models, application of Singapore Financial Reporting Standards, Singapore Standards on Auditing, management accounting, time management, leadership.